闇にそびえ立つ摩天楼
スターサイドホテル
The tall building that
looms in the darkness.
The Starside Hotel.
その一角で行われる
今宵のファイナルステージ
The final stage is taking place
in a small corner of it.
それは地上74メートルに
架けられた鉄骨
It's a gamble of death by
crossing a steel beam,
全長25メートルを渡る
死の橋渡り
25 metres in length,
74 metres from the ground...
クソッ クソッ　やるよ
Darn it, darn it!
I'll do it!
やりゃあいいんだろ　クソが！
All I have to do is
cross, right?!
カイジたちは今 摩天の地獄
Under the cold sky,
Kaiji and the rest...
その入り口に立っている
...are about to challenge
their worst fears.
Monster
これで８人
どうする？ほかの者は決したぞ
That makes eight of you.
What about you?
The rest have decided.
参加か？それとも権利放棄か
Do you want to take part
or forgo your chance?
な 何を…
やらぬ者が持っていても
W-What?!
They can't hold the tickets.
仕方あるまい
これは３着以下に譲ろう
These are for
the third place and lower!
お願いです　もう少し待って
ちょっと そんな
- Hey, you can't!
- Please wait a while more!
クズが！話にならぬ クズ
You trash!
No point talking
to you, trash!
もう少し待ってくれ？
Please wait a little
while more?
お前らは生まれてから
何度 そのセリフを吐いた？
You've said that countless times
since you were born, right?
The society isn't here
to mother you.
世間はお前らの母親ではない
クズの決心を
いつまでも待ったりはせん
Nobody will wait for trash like
you to make up their minds.
一生 迷ってろ
そして失い続けるんだ
You can stay lost forever.
All your valuable chances
will go to waste.
貴重なチャンスを
The first and second place ticket,
first-come-first-served.
１着券と２着券 先着順だ
我こそは と思う者は申し出ろ
Those who want it...
come forward!
俺が！
や やります
It'll be me!
I-I'll do it!
The 10 tickets for this last
stage have been given out!
決勝 10枚のチケットは
すべてさばかれた
同時にこのファイナルレースに
不参加の者は
Meanwhile, those who aren't
participating in the final stage...
...are herded away
by the men in black.
黒服によってステージを去り
残された10名は 橋を渡る順番を
決めるよう指示される
The 10 remaining will wait for
instructions to cross the bridge.
信じよう
Let's believe in it...
Though I'm not Tonegawa,
we've managed to cross it once.
利根川じゃねえが
みんな 一度は渡った橋
渡れる　渡れるはずだ
It can be crossed!
It should be possible!
Let's believe!
信じよう　自分たちを
Believe in yourselves!
渡れる　俺たちは渡れる
It can be done...
We can cross this!
Let's believe that
we can cross it.
｢信じよう｣｢渡れる｣
その言葉がすべて
They kept chanting those words
in a bid to survive.
生き残るため
彼らはその言葉を口にする
何というか
少しもったいない気もしますね
How should I put it...
I feel that it's such a waste.
ギャンブルとして
これ以上ない ショーだというのに
There's no show with
a greater gamble than this.
橋の向こうの部屋の方々は
Yet there're people who are
watching them cross...
テレビカメラでとらえた映像と
渡ってくる やつらを
...through the eyes of
a TV camera,
ただ食事をしながら
見物しておられるだけだなんて
just observing as they
have their meal.
It's all right. They're still
enjoying themselves.
いいのさ　めでるだけで
あちらの方々は
They weren't the ones
screaming away under the bridge.
下の橋でバカ騒ぎしていた
成り金どもとは違う
金の世界を牛耳る本物のＶＩＰ
They're the true wealthy people
who dominate the world of money.
資産家だ
ギャンブルなんて
もう とっくに卒業してらっしゃる
They have long graduated from
the arena called gambling.
あんなものは
貧乏人のやることとな
Such things are for
the poor.
賭けずともいい
賭けずとも十分 楽しめるんだ
They can still enjoy themselves,
even if they don't gamble.
人が恐れおののき 泣きながら
不安定な橋を渡っていく
The sight of people being terrified
at crossing an unstable bridge...
そのさまを
安定した場所から見ている
Being able to see that from
a place of comfort,
is more than enough
for them to enjoy it.
もう それだけで感じられるんだ
安全という名の愉悦をな
Watching it without
risking their lives...
That kind of pleasure is
more than you'd expect.
これが思いのほか 美味でな
だから賭ける必要などないのさ
There's no reason
to gamble.
さて 役得だ　高見の見物といくか
Well then, time to
enjoy ourselves.
We get the best view as spectators,
watching trash becoming stars.
クズどもが星になるさまを
勝てば救いの大金
しかし負ければ落下
If they win, they'll survive.
But if they lose, they'll
undoubtedly fall to their deaths!
まごうことなき死
掛け値なしの絶体絶命
It's a deadly situation
with no turning back!
And the order to cross
the death bridge is out.
そして決す
死の架け橋を渡る順番
右の橋の先頭は太田 以下
The order for the right bridge
will be Oota,
佐原 西田 藤野 秋川と続く
followed by Sahara, Nisida,
Fujino, and Akikawa.
左の橋の先頭は中村
Nakamura will be the first
to cross the left bridge,
これに中山 カイジ
石田 小泉が続く
followed by Nakayama, Kaiji,
Ishida and Koizumi.
俺が… 俺が１番… １番
I'm the first one...
First one...
渡れる　太田 俺たちは渡れる
You can cross it!
Oota! We can cross it!
渡れるんだ　足を貸せ
We can cross it!
Show me your feet!
いいから早く
Just do it already!
Feet?
足？
これは半ば おまじない
だが 半ば照準だ
Half of this is for luck.
The other is to adjust the aim.
照準？
Aim?
この線と鉄骨に刻まれた中心線を
合わせて歩くんだ
Always align this line right in
the centre of the steel beam.
それだけに集中して歩く
As long as you focus on that, you'll
definitely get to the other side.
気がつけば向こう側に着いてるさ
ただ この線はあくまで
ここが足の中心って目安で
But remember that this line is
for you to aim at your feet,
本当のそれとは微妙に ずれてる
and the centre of gravity from
your body will be slightly off.
その辺は歩きながら
微調整してくれ
So remember to adjust yourself
accordingly while crossing.
わ 分かった
G-Got it!
カイジ君　俺も… 俺にも頼む
Kaiji! Me too!
Please do it for me too!
俺も
M-Me too!
Me too!
俺にも頼む
俺も
Me too please!
Me too!
カイジさん　俺も…
- Me too! Me too!
- Kaiji, me too!
理が人の心を救うこともある
Reasons can save people
at times,
たとえそれが
どんなに か細い理であっても
regardless of how flimsy
a reasoning is.
今 目の前の状況に
押しつぶされそうな者には救い
For now, it's saving these people who
fear what they are about to face.
勇気を奮い立たせる
きっかけとなる
This might be the source of
courage that they need.
恐れるな
体の中心さえ ずらさなければ
Don't fear!
Your centre of gravity should be
stable so you won't fall!
100パーセント 落ちない
物理的に落ちないんだ
There's no way you will fall!
カイジ君
Kaiji!
Move forth slowly!
There's no need to panic!
ゆっくり進めばいい
焦らなくていいんだ
This time, it isn't a competition!
Nobody will push you from behind!
今度は競争じゃない
後ろから押されることはないんだ
敵はいない
自分のペースで行ける
There are no enemies!
Just do it at your own pace!
It's simple! It can be crossed!
簡単さ　渡れるに決まってる
いや　渡るぞ
１人残らず 全員渡る！
No...! We can easily cross it!
No one will be left behind!
Everyone will cross!
渡る…
渡る
We'll cross it.
We'll cross it!
渡る！
- We'll cross it!
渡る
渡る！
- We'll cross it! Let's go!
- Yeah, let's do it!
渡ろう　行ける
そうだ　行けるぞ！
チャチャッと渡って
こんな所から おさらばしようぜ
Let's hurry up, cross this and say
farewell to a place like this!
We'll be free from
the burden of the debts,
俺たちを押さえつけてきた
バカな借金 忌まわしい重しを
those heavy deadweight
in our lives!
人生からどけるんだ
そうだ！
Yeah, that's right!
そのために ここ１回を勝とう
For that to happen,
we need to win this once!
勝ちきる　俺たちはできる
We need to win this cleanly!
We can do this!
俺たちは押してくる敵がいる橋を
一度 やり遂げてるんだ
We're done with crossing the bridge
that had enemies pushing us!
それに比べたら
はるかに簡単　楽勝だ
Compared to that,
this task is easy!
俺たちはやれる
We can do this!
Yeah, we can do it!
Let's do it!
やれる
そうだ
It can be done!
- That's right!
- Kaiji!
カイジ君！
やれるんだ
It can be done!
- Yeah! It can be done!
- We can do it!
やれる
やれるんだ
まるで悲鳴だな
To me, it's a cry
of desperation!
あおられて その気になる
They are getting fired up
over that.
そんなものは偽りの奮起
エセもいいとこ
That is a false encouragement...
All lies.
目を背けているだけだ　真実から
Make believe may be good,
内心は恐怖に身も心も震えている
but it just blinds the person
from reality...
あんな まやかしの決起は
They are shivering
with fear inside.
そう 橋に乗って
５メートルで吹っ飛ぶ
As one walks 5 metres into the bridge,
that false motivation will vanish.
そして真実が顔を出す
And then reality will smack
them right in the face!
やつらは恐ろしいのだ
They are afraid.
It's because they are afraid.
恐ろしいからこそ ああして
自分を奮い立たせ 酔っている
That's why they get
themselves drunk.
それはあの男 カイジも同様
That man, Kaiji...
will face the same situation.
Really? Well, at least, he...
そうでしょうか？
少なくとも やつは…
連中をあおってる時 やつの言葉が
変化していったのに気づいたか？
When firing those people up, didn't
you notice changes in his words?
変化？
最初 あの男は
Changes?
At first that man said,
"We'll cross this bridge".
｢この橋を渡る｣と言っていたが
途中でそれは｢できる｣になり
Then it was "Can be done". And at
the end, it became "Can do".
話の終わりでは｢やれる｣になった
なぜだか分かるか？
Do you understand why?
恐れているんだ やつも
He's afraid as well.
恐れているからこそ
｢渡る｣という直接的な表現を避け
Because he's afraid,
he didn't use terms like "cross",
｢できる｣｢やれる｣などと
言いかえた
and changed it to "can be done"
and "can do".
無意識に逃げているんだ
｢渡る｣という行為からな
He's subconsciously evading the
act of walking across the bridge.
言葉とは裏腹に その内心は
恐怖に震えているわけだ
Despite what he said,
he's really afraid too.
恐ろしい　恐ろしい
Afraid... Afraid... Afraid...
Afraid...
恐ろしい…
Afraid.
盛り上がってるところ すまないが
Excuse me, but the cutoff time
for the exchange is 1:30am.
換金の締め切りは午前１時半
今 ０時25分　そろそろ
出発したほうが賢明だと思うが？
It's 12:25 am now.
Shouldn't we begin this soon?
出発の時 来たる
The time to depart
has come!
恐れるな
できるぞ
- Don't be scared! It can be done!
- It can be done! Do it!
できる
負けるな
- Nakamura!
- It can be done!
中村　できる！
俺は さっきの橋では
ぶっちぎりの１位
I arrived first on the previous
bridge! No one even came close!
影も踏ませなかった
それと同じことをやるだけだ
I just have to repeat my feat!
That's right, Nakamura!
そうだ 中村！
同じことだ
It's the same!
できる　できる　できる
It can be done!
This is definitely possible!
これは できることなんだ
He's off!
行った…
行け！中村
- Go, Nakamura! You can do it!
- Go, go, go for it!
中村　行け！
行け！
- Well done, keep it up!
- Na-Nakamura!
な 中村…
行け　行けるぞ 太田
- You can do it! Oota!
- Go, go for it!
- Go! Continue!
- Keep that up, go!
太田　いいぞ
行け 太田！
Oota, go for it!
Well done, Oota!
中村が口火を切ると
それに引っ張られるように
With Nakamura off, they
continued along one by one.
次々と続いた
Sahara, carry on!
That is the reason for
their morale.
そのさまは戦意の発露
強気に意を決して
自分の人生を切り開こうとする
Their firm belief is cutting off what
has burdened them in their lives.
そんな行為に見える
That is how it is.
続け！
おおっ　西田！
I can do it!
That's right, you can do it!
続け！
カイジ君
- Kaiji! Kaiji!
- However, it is not the same!
が 違う
違う　これは決意なんかじゃねえ
This isn't determination.
いっときの激情に酔い
This is just a moment of frenzy.
It's trying to suppress true feelings.
まっとうな感覚を
吹っ飛ばそうとする
単なる勢い　勢いだけ…
This is just pure will,
pure will...
ごまかし… だが
I'm merely deceiving myself.
But for now... I have to...
I have to... believe it!
今は… 今は酔わなきゃダメ
That's because this is
an escape route!
なぜなら これは離脱
Kaiji, Kaiji!
己が存在の基盤
大地からの離脱
An escape from the root of our
existence! An escape from reality!
One who is completely sane
would never do this!
まっとうな神経じゃ踏み出せねえ
時 ０時40分
It's 12:40 am now.
希望のゴールへと続く
ファイナルレース
The final hurdle to achieve
the goal of hope continues...
死の橋渡り 開始
The crossing of
the death bridge begins!
Everyone was silent on the bridge.
The shouts at the start were gone.
スタートまでの騒ぎとは
打って変わり
橋に踏み出してからは皆 無言
せき払い１つない
Nobody even dared to cough.
圧倒的な闇と静寂の中を
ただ10人は行く
The ten of them just carried on,
engulfed by the darkness and silence.
Don't think about it!
Let it go from the head!
考えるな　マヒさせろ
自分の中にある感覚を遮断
眠らせろ
Let the feeling within myself
be gone... Let it go!
集中するんだ
前に進むことだけに
Concentrate!
Just move forward!
カイジは懸命に
抑えようとしていた
Kaiji tries to push away
the anxieties within him,
and the devilish voice
inside his heart...
心の中にある深い闇
魔物の声を
そしてそれは ほかの者も同じ
And that is the same
for the rest of them!
皆 懸命に抑えつけていた
Everyone is desperately
forcing it back.
もうメッキは剥がれた
さっきまでの大騒ぎは
The coating has already
come undone.
The wild noises made earlier
resembled cheap rocket fireworks.
言うなら
安物のロケット花火のようなもの
橋に乗った途端
心は冷え 恐怖が頭をもたげる
The instant they got on the bridge,
their hearts froze and fear emerged.
もうすぐ開く
魔物を招き入れての宴の扉がな
It will soon open...
The door into the feast which
they were invited to by demons.
人は生まれながら
心の中に魔物を飼っている
As humans grow, they
feed the demon within as well.
普段は心の最も深い部屋に
閉じ込め
Normally, that devil's locked
within the depths of the darkness,
鍵をかけ 忘れようとしている
and is locked away,
forgotten...
だが…
However...
鍵も扉も所詮 無力
In the end, the door and
the lock are totally useless.
In just moments, that demon
will break loose and appear.
そんなもの あっという間に
こじあけて 現れる怪物
死という名の魔物
"Death" is the name
of that demon...
それがまもなく連中を襲う
And that will strike them
very soon.
人の夢や希望　目標
The hopes and dreams
of humans...
Their targets, plans,
cooperation and sincerity,
計画　協力や親切
愛情　優しさ…
love and kindness...
そのすべてを握りつぶす
魔物の中の魔物
All that will be crushed,
by the demon amongst the demons.
生きとし 生ける者
すべてを支配している死の恐怖
All living creatures are
controlled by the fear of death.
その圧倒的かつ冷酷な真実
That is the overwhelming
cold, hard truth.
それをやつらは
あの橋の上で思い出す
Those guys on the bridge
will think of this.
これほど違うものか
It's not that different!
落ちても助かるという状況と
落ちたら死ぬ
To fall and still be safe,
and to fall and die.
即死という状況では これほど…
The situation known as
certain death is not so different!
やば… 嫌な気分だぜ
This is bad...
I have a bad feeling about this.
何かが胸の中に湧いてきてる
Something is swelling up
within my heart...
まるで心臓を
It's as if cold hands are
gripping my heart tightly.
冷えた両手で
わしづかみにされるような
そんな悪寒
That devilish coldness...
Bad... This is bad...!
This feeling is bad!
まずい… まずい！
この感情は
この感情は 俺を殺す
This feeling...
will get me killed!
殺される　クソッ
I'm being killed!
Darn it! What should I do?!
What should I do?
どうしたらいい？どうしたら…
何だよ　何だよ これ
What's this? What's this?!
しっかりしろ しっかり
Get a grip! Get a...?!
W-What was it?!
な 何だよ
何なんだよ 今の
W-What was that...
just now...?!
変だぞ 俺
This is strange...
俺の体が 俺のものじゃ
ないみたいな この感覚
This feeling is as if
my body is no longer mine...
フワフワして…
こんな調子じゃ とても無理
I feel unsteady. With this
condition, it is impossible!
渡れない　落ちちまう
落ち…
I can't cross...
I'll fall...
I don't like this...!
I don't want to fall...!
嫌だ　落ちたくない
落ちたくない　落ちたくない
I don't want to fall!
I don't want to!
生きたい　生きたい
I want to live!
生きたい！
I want to live!!
金もいらない　何もいらない
I don't need money,
I don't need anything!
40まで借金生活でもいい
何でもいいんだ
It's okay to be in debt till
I'm 40! Anything is fine!
ただ生きたい
I just want to live!
こんな…
こんな簡単で単純なことに
It was...
It was always so simple...
ここまで…
ここまで追い詰められなきゃ
But up till now...
It has always
driven me all this while...
To think that I didn't
realise it until now!
気がつかないなんて
カイジ君　違うよ
Kaiji... It's completely
different!
The previous bridge and
this one are totally different!
さ さっきまでの橋と全然 違うよ
言うな
カイジ君
Don't say it...
- Kaiji...
- Don't say it!
言うな　同じだ
It's the same!
It is the same!
同じなんだよ　何も変わらない
Nothing has changed!
変わらないんだ
風…？風だ
The wind!
There's wind!
冗談じゃねえ
You're kidding me! If the wind
starts to blow now...
今 風なんかにあおられたら…
吹いてない　吹いてないぞ
It's not blowing,
It is not blowing!
本当だ
It's true!
吹いてない　気のせいだ
No, it's just your imagination!
何言ってんだよ　風だよ　風が！
What nonsense are you saying?!
There is wind!
Oota?! Oota,
hang in there!
太田！太田　しっかりしろ
飛ばされるー
I'm being blown away!
太田　顔を上げろ　上げろったら
Oota!! Look up! I said look up!
よく見るんだ　吹いてない
風は吹いてない
Look carefully! It's not blowing!
The wind isn't blowing!
落ち着け 太田　落ち着け
Calm down, Oota!
Calm down!
太田！
Oota...!!
始まったな
It has begun.
風…
太田
- The wind. Wind!
- Oota, Oota!
太田　お前が
風だと感じているのは幻
The wind you're feeling is
an illusion! It's imaginary!
幻覚だ　幻覚なんだ 太田
- Someone... Save me!
- It's an illusion, Oota!
助けて！
落ち着け 太田
Save me!!
Calm down! Oota!
と… 飛ばされる
誰か！飛ばされる
I'm being blown away!
Can someone... help me?!
ば… バカ野郎　触るな
F-Fool! Don't touch it!
さっき見ただろ　その橋には
高圧電流が流れてんだぞ
You saw it earlier, right? The bridge
has high volts passing through!
Sahara! What are you doing?!
Stop him! Support him!
佐原　何してる　止めろ！
支えるんだ
バカ言うな　できるか そんなこと
Don't say such a stupid thing!
I can't do that!
佐原！
無理だ
- Sahara!
- It's impossible!
ここで人を支えるなんて無理！
It's impossible
to support someone here!
自分がバランスを取るので
精いっぱいなんだぞ
I'm already at my wit's end
trying to maintain my balance!
巻き添え食ったら
俺まで感電して落ちちまうんだ
If I get dragged into it,
I'll lose it and fall too!
冗談じゃねえ　救えねえ
I can't save him! I can't do
a single thing about it!
I'm being blown away!!
どうにもならねえ
どうにもならねえよ
太田　聞こえるか？
やめろ　触るな
Oota! Can you hear me?!
Stop it! Don't touch it!
- Don't touch it!
- Look at me! Oota, look!
俺を見ろ 太田　見ろ
見るんだ 太田　見ろ
Look, Oota, look at me!
Look here!
No, please!!
こっちを見ろ　見ろったら
頼むから見てくれ
Look at me!
Please look at me, look!
見ろ　俺を見ろ！
誰か助けて！
- Look at me!
- Someone save me!!
Look, Oota! Oota!!
見るんだ 太田　太田！
太田！
Oota!!
１人…
One person.
太田…
Oota...
もう 嫌だ
I don't... want this anymore!
もう嫌だ　こんな橋！
I had enough of this bridge!
落ち着け 秋川　落ち着け
Calm down, Akikawa! Calm down!
嫌だ　戻る　戻ろう
No, I'm heading back!
Let's go back!
よせ
Stop it!
Go back please!
誰か…
石田さん
- Ishida!!
- Someone... Someone help me!
落ち着け　みんな落ち着け
Calm down!
Everyone calm down!
誰か！死にたくない
I don't want to die!
落ち着け
Calm down!
Save me... Save me!
助けて… 助けてくれ
Calm down, everyone!!
落ち着くんだ　みんな！
時 ０時44分
It's 12:44 am now.
命をかけた ファイナルレース
There're 8 persons left betting
their lives on the final race.
残り８名
その先に待つのは希望の光か
それとも
Does the light of hope
await in front of them?
Or is it the darkness of
hopelessness?
絶望という名の闇か
次回 ｢亡霊｣
Next, Dying Spirit.